A Guide to the William Faulkner Collection,
Special Collections Department, University of Virginia Library
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
William Faulkner Collection 1884-1965
Special Collections, University of Virginia Library
6271-bb
This collection consists of 16 items.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
There are no restrictions on access to the Library's microfilms of the William Faulkner manuscripts in its custody; the microfilm may be consulted by any interested party, and it will be lent through the interlibrary loan system. Materials are constantly added. Long-term loans may be arranged. Use of the microfilm will be restricted to the premises of the borrowing library. No loans will be made to individuals. Researchers should enquire of the Manuscripts Division concerning availability of microfilm of manuscripts that are pertinent to their work. Most of the literary manuscripts in our collections written by Faulkner, both holograph and typescript, have also been published in facsimile in William Faulkner Manuscripts, 25 vols (New York: Garland, 1986-87).
By the terms of the agreement by which the William Faulkner Foundation transferred the original manuscripts to the University, access to the original manuscripts is restricted (to ensure the survival of the physically-delicate originals) to doctoral candidates at the dissertation stage of their programs, and to certain mature scholars and critics. But even these researchers must demonstrate need to see the originals that goes beyond the requirements of most routine research. A doctoral candidate at the dissertation stage, or other qualified researcher who believes that his or her work requires access to the originals must correspond with the Curator of Manuscripts prior to arrival at the Library to obtain permission for access.
No microfilm, electrostatic, or other types of copies may be made of materials written by William Faulkner that are in our William Faulkner Collections. Other materials in the collections may be copied subject to the normal rules of the Library established under the conditions of the Copyright Act. All copying is performed by the Printing Services Department of the University.
Acquisition Information
Presented to the Rare Book Department by Linton R. Massey.
Scope and Content Information
Microfilm of printed material relating to William Faulkner and Col. Falkner.
Contents List
- The Oxford Eagle 1936 Nov 26 - 1939 May 4
  Reel 1
- The Oxford Eagle 1939 May 11 - 1941 Dec 4
  Reel 2
- The Oxford Eagle 1941 Dec 11 - 1944 July 6
  Reel 3
- The Oxford Eagle 1944 Jul 13 - 1946 Dec 19
  Reel 4
- The Oxford Eagle 1946 Dec 19 - 1948 Dec 23
  Reel 5
- The Oxford Eagle 1948 Dec 23 - 1950 Sep 28
  Reel 6
- The Oxford Eagle 1950 Oct 5 - 1952 May 1
  Reel 7
- The Oxford Eagle 1952 May 1 - 1953 Dec 17
  Reel 8
- The Oxford Eagle 1965 Apr 25
  Reel 9:A, ("William Faulkner - Souvenir Edition")
- Rocky Mountain Review 1942
  Reel 9:B, Volume 6, Nos. 3-4 Spring-Summer, "A Note on Faulkner's Style" by Warren Beck regarding descriptive passages, 3 frames.
- Scrutiny 1933
  Reel 9:B, Cambridge, England (II) "Dostoevsky or Dickens?" by F.R. Leavis regarding Faulkner's Light in August, style more like Dickens than Dostoevsky, 2 frames.
- Bonniers Litterara Magasin Dec 1950
  Reel 9:B, (Danish), "William Faulkner" by Aka Sanzon regarding many of Faulkner's books in synopsis, 6 frames.
- Confluences Nov 1941
  Reel 9:B, (French). A review by Marc Borkezat regarding Faulkner's transformation of ordinary words into explosive and emphatic descriptions. "L'avenier du roman" by Henry Malherlee (?) regarding Faulkner's full descriptive pictures paralleled to lyrical melodies, musical symphonies, and tonal qualities.
- Prevues June 1952
  Reel 9:B. "Apropos d'une phrase de Faulkner" by unknown regarding Faulkner and Andre Malraux as the creative force and "muscle" of Europe and America.
- Les Lettres Nouvelles Dec 1956
  Reel 9:B. (French) play. "Le Capitaine de Kopenick" (fin) by Carl Zuckmayer.
- Ripley Advertiser and Southern Sentinel1880-1889 and 1884-1891
  Reel 9:C. Various issues, containing articles by and about Col. William Falkner.